ncpgambling.org 2005-12-14

# National Council on Problem Gambling - Privacy Policy

Regarding information collected via this Web site

**National Council on Problem Gambling adheres to the highest ethical standards** in gathering, using, and safeguarding information submitted via this Web site.

**National Council on Problem Gambling limits access to information** collected via this Web site to those staff members who require the information to carry out their business functions; all staff are educated about practices and policies to safeguard that information, and those policies are carefully enforced.

**Is it safe to use my credit card online?**  
National Council on Problem Gambling protects your online transaction and personal information by appropriate security safeguards. Your personal information transmissions, including your payment information, will be encrypted by SSL technology.

**Third parties that support National Council on Problem Gambling must agree to safeguard information** in the same manner as does National Council on Problem Gambling. Only third parties that require information collected via this Web site in order to support National Council on Problem Gambling are provided with such information.

**National Council on Problem Gambling makes all reasonable efforts to accurately and securely maintain** information collected via the Web site. National Council on Problem Gambling monitors and adopts applicable technologies designed to aid in the accuracy and security of information gathered via this Web site.

**Information is collected only when visitors to the site voluntarily provide it.** Visitors to this site who do not wish for their personally identifiable information to be collected are asked not to provide such information.

**Information submitted via this Web site may be stored and used** by National Council on Problem Gambling to better understand the needs of visitors to the site, to inform visitors of offers that may be of interest to them, and to improve National Council on Problem Gambling.

**If you have provided your E-mail address and wish to remove it** from National Council on Problem Gambling mailing lists, please send an E-mail message to [unsubscribe@ncpgambling.org](mailto:unsubscribe@ncpgambling.org). National Council on Problem Gambling will make reasonable efforts to delete your E-mail from existing files.

**National Council on Problem Gambling has no intention of collecting information from children** that may be personally identifiable, including names, addresses, telephone numbers, or E-mail addresses; children are asked not to submit such information. If a child has provided National Council on Problem Gambling with personally identifiable information, the child's parent should request that the child's information be removed from existing files.

**This Web site may collect information that is NOT personally identifiable** from any visitor to the site, including the visitor's operating system, browser, domain name, and the specific Web pages on National Council on Problem Gambling's Web site that the visitor accesses. Such information is used to improve National Council on Problem Gambling's Web site.

**Visitors to National Council on Problem Gambling's Web site are informed** that National Council on Problem Gambling may store some information on a visitors computer in the form of a "cookie" or similar file. These files allow National Council on Problem Gambling to tailor its Web site to reflect the visitors listed or historical preferences. Most Web browsers notify a user when such a file is stored and allow the user to erase or block such files in his/her computer, as per the browser's instructions.
